http://www.accme.org/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy General Information
Thank you for using our websites. This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") was created to inform you of the types of information we collect from you when you access and use the entire group of websites and webpages owned, operated, licensed, or controlled by the Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (“ACCME”). By using our website (“Site”), you acknowledge and agree to how the ACCME collects and uses information about you.
International Visitors
The Site is available throughout the world for different purposes. The Site shall be operated in accordance with laws of the United States and visitors to the Site should be aware that the laws of the United States may differ from those of their respective countries of residence.
By providing your personal information as an international visitor or user, you are: (i) permitting the transfer of your personal information to the United States, which may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you reside; and (ii) permitting the use of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
If you reside outside the United States, the ACCME will not use your personal information in any way except (i) insofar as such processing is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and ACCME or (ii) as may be required by applicable law.
You can request to access, update, or correct your personal information. You may have additional rights pursuant to your local law applicable to the processing of your personal information. For example, if the processing of your personal information is subject to GDPR, and your personal information is processed based on legitimate interests, as described above, you have the right to object to the processing on grounds relating to your specific situation. Under GDPR you may also have the right to request to have your personal information deleted or restricted, and ask for portability of your personal information. The ACCME keeps your personal information for only as long as we need it for the purposes for which we collect it, or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law.
If you desire to exercise any of your rights under GDPR, please contact the ACCME at:
Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME)
401 N. Michigan Ave.
Suite 1850
Chicago, IL 60611
United States of America
Email: info@accme.org
In the event you consider our processing of your personal information not to be compliant with the applicable data protection laws, you can file a complaint directly with the ACCME at the address noted above or with the competent data protection authority. The name and contact details of the Data Protection Authorities in the European Union can be found here.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
The terms of this Privacy Policy may change without warning. It is your responsibility to check for changes. Any change shall become effective once it is posted to this Privacy Policy. The effective date listed below will note the last time a change was made and posted to this Privacy Policy.
Last Updated: April 8, 2019
What general types of information does this Site collect?
This Site collects personally identifiable information (“PII”), non-personal information (“NPI”), and aggregate information (“AI”).
What are the differences and definitions of the different types of information collected by this Site?
Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”): Personally Identifiable Information is information that can be used to reveal your identity.
Non-Personal Information (“NPI”): Non-Personal Information is information that is related to an individual user but does not individually identify that user. An example would include Internet Protocol (“IP”) address.
Aggregate Information (“AI”): Aggregate Information refers to non-personal information of an aggregated nature including number of clicks, number of visitors, links hit, etc. overall for the Site and is not related to any one individual user.
What specific information do we collect?
Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”): We may collect your full name, mailing and/or billing address including street name and street number, gender, age, city, state, zip and apartment or suite number if applicable, phone number (could be any combination of mobile, office and home), email address (home and/or business), emergency contact information, names and contact information of people you nominate, usernames, passwords, credentials you provide, stories or other information you submit about yourself or others, and any information required by the credit card company or by Payment Card Industry security standards to verify your identity on a credit card transaction including but not limited to your credit card number, date of credit expiration, and security code.
Non-Personal Information (“NPI”): We may collect from users their IP address, browser type, domain name, the pages accessed, the time of access, the previous site before accessing this Site, statistics related to usage of educational tools, the length of time on the Site, the link that brought the user to the Site, and other non-personal related information.
Aggregate Information (“AI”): We may collect in aggregate form the number of users accessing the Site, the pages accessed, the clicks per page, the number of links accessed, and other non-personal aggregated information not tied to a specific user.
How do we collect the information?
For Personally Identifiable Information, generally we collect it from the information you provide to the Site such as when you submit a user form, register for a product or service, when you contact us, or purchase a product or service. However, we may also collect such information from other sources including our affiliates and from third parties that we contract with to process credit cards, process applications, or send communications.
What do we do with the information we collect? Why are we collecting this information?
We collect PII for multiple purposes that may include membership registration, event registration, help you update username/password, to look up your information if needed, for credit card processing, for collecting donations or fees, registration for special gaming programs or educational opportunities, on user inputted forms for various purposes including but not limited to nominating honorees for awards, for inquiries, for comments, suggestions, or other user forms, for mailing and communication purposes, and for access to tools we offer.
NPI & AI: We collect Non-Personal and Aggregate Information in order that we may better understand how you use the Site, update our Site content, understand trends, for demographic informational purposes, improve the Site experience, and perform non-personal or aggregate statistics.
We may also use the information we collect (including PI, NPI, and AI) to meet legal and regulatory obligations, to protect the property of the ACCME, and to better offer our services or products.
Do we share any of the Personally Identifiable Information we collect?
We may share or disclose any information we collect about you including Personally Identifiable Information with our affiliates. We may also share or disclose such PII with third parties whom we have contracted with for the purposes of carrying out the purposes of registration, marketing, communications or credit card processing.
Do we share any of the Personally Identifiable Information we collect about you with third parties for their direct marketing purposes?
No. However, ACCME may use information collected to help improve services, products, and offerings available and sent to you from the ACCME.
Do we use cookies, beacons, or pixel tags?
Cookies
Cookies are small text files sent to your hard drive when you visit a website. From time to time we may use cookies for different reasons including to make your user experience more enjoyable, to track what pages you visit, to keep track of your login information so it is available for you when need it, and for other purposes. Cookies can be required, meaning they are necessary for the proper functioning of our Site or a portion of our Site. We do not currently use flash cookies.
Opt Out – Cookies
You can opt-out of cookies by adjusting your browser settings. However, if you opt-out of cookies, portions of the Site may not function normally or you may be prevented from utilizing certain aspects.
Google Analytics
From time to time we may use Google Analytics that will allow us to review anonymous data regarding the gender, age, browser device used, device used (including if it is a mobile device), domain name, date and time of access, and interests of Site users to adapt our Site content to better reflect such users’ needs and interests. Google Analytics uses cookies in achieving this. This information is collected through your Google ad settings but it is not providing any PII.
Opt Out – Google Analytics
You can opt-out of this feature using Google Ad settings or through the Google Analytics opt-out browser.
Web Beacons, Pixel Tags, Clear GIFs and other technologies
From time to time we may use web beacons, pixel tags, clear gifs, or other technologies (“Other Technologies”) that allow your information to be tracked across sites for the purposes of advertising or remarketing such as Google’s Remarketing AdWords Program as well as other similar programs (See Google Remarketing Below)
Google Remarketing
Google Remarketing is a dynamic interactive online advertising behavioral algorithm and process that provides for you to receive targeted ads across many sites based on your suspected interests gathered from your operation of this Site and other websites. It achieves this by connecting your activities on this Site with the AdWords advertising network and the DoubleClick Cookie. This means that you may see ads on other sites behaviorally targeted to you with the intent of being something that is in your frame of interest based on your use of this Site and other sites where Google Remarketing is operating. Cookies are used to track your behavior for this advertising remarketing. While this does not track PII, it may be possible to combine this information with PII about you. You can opt out of the cookie for remarketing tracking here: Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.
You can also opt out of Google Remarketing by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page. Google has additional information available about their Remarketing Privacy Guidelines, Policies, and Restrictions.
Do Not Track
Our Site does NOT react to Do Not Track options you set in your browser.
Transmissions
You acknowledge that any communications or transmissions to or from this Site may not be completely private even if such efforts are made to secure the privacy of such as communications and transmissions can be intercepted.
Third Party Personally Identifiable Information (PII)
You acknowledge that you have secured permission from any third party from which you report to us PII on such third party. For instance, if you report to us a name and email address as someone you nominate for an award or recognition, we are relying on you under terms of this Privacy Policy that you have received the permission from such third party for us to use that PII on third party according to the terms herein.
Third Party Links and Other sites
This Site may contain links to third parties for multiple purposes such as for convenience, for additional information or content, or for processing forms, credit cards and for other purposes. In any case, those sites are likely to have a separate privacy policy which you are responsible to read. ACCME takes no responsibility for those sites’ privacy policies, for the content on such sites, or for their policies of collecting information.
Security of Your Information
In accordance with the applicable laws and regulations, we have taken adequate technical and organizational measures to safeguard the security of your personal information. We store the personal information that we process on a secure database that is protected by technical access controls. We periodically review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems.
Please be advised that while we strive to protect your personally identifiable data, we make no guarantees or assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, access, or misuse and are not responsible in the event that such loss or misuse occurs.
Contacting Us
Your privacy is important to the ACCME. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:
Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME)
401 N. Michigan Ave.
Suite 1850
Chicago, IL 60611
United States of America
Email: info@accme.org
401 N. Michigan Ave. - Suite 1850 - Chicago, IL - 60611 (312) 527-9200
© 2019 ACCME All Rights Reserved
Lower Footer
Privacy Policy
